氣候管理，節約能源
Climate controlled stacks, energy efficient,
整個收藏可能  可以都塞進電子書內
now mind you the whole collection  could probably fit on a Kindle,
不過至少學生們  又多了個躲雨的地方
but at least the cadets will have  another place to get out of the rain.
你有參與設計嗎？
Did you have much input on the design?
藍圖有經過我的認可
I approved the blue prints.
如果要簽上我的名字  就必須保證蓋得很好
If something's gonna have my name on it,  I want to make damn sure they build it right.
我老公大概自以為是建築師吧
I think my husband fancies himself a bit  of an architect.
傑弗遜設計了蒙蒂塞洛…
Well, Jefferson designed Monticello...
他也跟自己的奴隸上床
He also fucked his slaves.
幸好我沒有奴隸
Luckily I don't have any,
所以這種誘惑還沒出現
so that particular temptation  hasn't presented itself.
山特諾  南卡羅來納州第一軍事學院
The Sentinel,  South Carolina's premiere military college.
教會我榮譽、責任和尊重
They taught me the values of honor,  duty and respect.
也迷惑我，試圖擊垮我  大四的時候差點把我退學
They also hazed me, tried to break me,  and senior year, nearly expelled me
因為我去當參議員競選志工  導致成績下滑
when I volunteered for a Senate race  and my studies suffered.
但這沒阻止他們在30年後
But that didn't stop them  from soliciting a hefty sum
來向我募款興建新圖書館
for their new library 30 years later.
在權力和金錢的影響下  壞成績很快就被遺忘了
How quickly poor grades are forgotten  in the shadow of power and wealth.
你的酒才半滿，法蘭
Your drink is only about half as full  as it should be, Frank.
你想把我灌醉嗎？
Are you trying to get me drunk?
醉倒在水溝裏  這樣我才能偷走你老婆
Drunk, passed out in the gutter  so I can steal your wife.
你有收到關於  步槍兵的電子郵件嗎？
Did you get the email about the Riflemen?
什麼電子郵件？
What email?
我辦公室發的邀請函  我本來希望能看到他們
From my office. About the invitations.  I was hoping they would be here.
我再查一下名單  但我不記得有電子郵件…
I'll check the list,  but I don't remember any email...
沒關係，我只是好奇而已
Oh, not a problem. I was just wondering.
法蘭，對不起…
Shit, Frank, I'm sorry...
別想太多
Don't you sweat it for a second.
你現在就可以補償我
In fact, here's how you can make it up to me,
- 幫我把酒倒滿  - 沒問題
-freshen my drink.  -That I can do.
恭喜你，議員
Congratulations, Congressman.
瑞米，很高興在這裏見到你
Remy, nice to see you here.
蓋瑞和善可工業的人  要我問候你
Gerry and all the folks at SanCorp  give you their regards.
真遺憾他們不能來
Well, I'm sorry they couldn't make it.
克萊兒呢？
Where's Claire?
她在附近拒絕她的仰慕者
She's here somewhere, fending off admirers.
善可工業對於  她謝絕捐款的事很失望
SanCorp was very disappointed  she turned down their donation.
我想也是
I can imagine.
他們對於彼得魯索  競選州長也有顧慮
And they're also concerned  about Peter Russo running for governor.
你怎麼知道？
Now, how do you know about that?
四分之三個賓州  都在馬塞勒斯頁岩上
Three-quarters of Pennsylvania  sits on top of the Marcellus Shale.
如果我連誰要選州長都不知道
If I can't find out  who's running for governor,
那我根本不配領薪水
I don't deserve a dime  of what they're paying me.
法蘭斯安德沃圖書館
This Watershed Bill Russo sponsors  places a lot of restrictions on drilling...
魯索支持的分水嶺提案  在鑽井方面設置很多限制…
瑞米，國會現在休會  這週末也不談工作
Remy, Congress is in recess  and this weekend is not about work.
抱歉，你說的有道理
I apologize, you are absolutely right.
- 善可工業是你唯一的客戶嗎？  - 我有很多客戶
-ls SanCorp your only account?  -I have plenty.
但別的客戶沒贊助你的圖書館  也沒出我的機票錢
But my other clients didn't pay for  your library, or my plane ticket down here.
一次難得的觀光機會  希望你喜歡這裏的景色
Yes, nice little junket for you.  I do hope you're taking in the sights.
我不是第一次來查爾斯頓
This isn't my first trip to Charleston.
但我相信是第一次  不以我的新聞秘書身份來吧
But I'll bet it's your first time  not as my Press Secretary.
對
It is.
今晚還要見誰？
Who else you have coming in?
我不想讓今晚太忙
I didn't want to pack tonight too much.
這種酒會常是  為了你這種金主辦的
You know, these receptions are usually  just for the money people, like yourself.
一般我會站在這裏
Normally, this is where I would start
講一些山特諾的歷史  或哲學之類的廢話…
to drone on about the Sentinel's history,  its philosophy, its yadda, yadda, yadda...
但這些話  我要留到明天演講時說
But I'm gonna save that  for my big speech tomorrow,
免得你們要無聊兩次
and that way I'm not gonna  bore y'all to tears twice.
今晚我們邀請到這位  不用我介紹的人
Tonight we're gonna turn it over  to a man who needs no introduction,
因為我們都知道他這小賤人
'cause we all know  what a son of a bitch he is.
說真的
Seriously, though,
法蘭安德沃  是我們教導學生德行的榜樣
Frank Underwood exemplifies all the virtues  we try to instill in our graduates.
法蘭，很榮幸能稱你為校友
We're so proud to call you  an alumnus, Frank,
把你的名字  永遠留在我們校園裏
and to have your name  as a permanent fixture on our campus.
法蘭安德沃議員
Congressman Frank Underwood.
謝謝，希更斯校長
Thank you, President Higgins.
我要先感謝善可工業
I first want to thank SanCorp Industries
他們提供資金  實現新圖書館的想法
for providing the funds  to make the library possible.
我剛入學時
When I matriculated here as a young cadet,
吉米卡特剛當選總統
Jimmy Carter had just been  elected President.
我畢業時
After I graduated,
我和吉米有同樣的願望  希望能再待四年
I wished that I could have had  another four years, just like Jimmy.
我們兩人都未能如願  但我帶著美好回憶畢業
Well, neither of us got our wish,  but I left this campus with fond memories.
我第一次…
The first time I ever...
我有收到你的電子郵件
I got your damn email.
這燈閃多久了？
How long has that light been like that?
大概一個月了
I don't know. A month, maybe.
沒人來修嗎？
And nobody's come to fix it?
這裏不會有人來修東西
Nobody don't fix nothing around here.
- 你有叫人修嗎？  - 我在看電視
-Well have you asked?  -I'm watching.
別管了，我習慣了
Leave it alone. I'm used to it now.
- 好多了吧？  - 現在太暗了
-Better, huh?  -Now it's too dark.
- 為什麼關電視？  - 媽，聽著
-What'd you do that for?  -Listen, Ma.
我要競選州長
I'm running for governor.
過幾天就會宣佈  所以我才回來費城
I'm gonna announce in a few days.  That's why I came up to Philly.
明天有個社區會議
There's a community meeting tomorrow.
我要跟造船工人談  計劃幫他們爭回工作
I'm gonna talk to the shipbuilders  about a plan to bring their jobs back,
讓他們在選舉中支持我
so they support me in the election.
我完全聽不懂
I don't know nothing about that stuff.  It's over my head.
新聞裏會出現關於我的報導
Okay, listen, there's gonna be some stories  coming out about me, in the news,
關於我的過去
about my past.
我只想先提醒你  以免你嚇一跳
I just wanted to give you a heads up,  so it doesn't catch you off guard.
我早就不看新聞了，都是垃圾
I don't watch the news no more.  Bunch of garbage.
你想看凱文和莎拉的照片嗎？
You want to see some pictures  of Kevin and Sarah?
太暗了看不到
Too dark to look at pictures.
在我手機上，不用開燈
No, no, it's on my phone,  you don't need any light.
拿走，我討厭那些東西
Get it away from me. I hate those things.
會得腦癌
Brain cancer.
不只是在樓上，還是三樓
It wasn't just up the stairs,  it was up three flights of stairs,
在科學大樓裏
in the science building.
古丘肯海默說…
And Gluckenheimer, what he did...
「你今天真美，州長夫人」
"Well, you look lovely today, Mrs. Governor."
然後它拉了坨屎
And the thing took a dump.
他們牽不回來…
Right. And they couldn't get it back...
你可以把一頭牛牽上三樓  但牽不下來！
You can get a cow up three flights of stairs,  but you can't get it down!
所以最後他才說  「誰晚餐想吃牛排？」
And that's why in the end he said,  "Who wants steak for dinner?"
- 你們玩得開心嗎？  - 我們很好
-How are you boys doing?  -We're good.
- 我胖嗎？  - 拒答
-You think I'm fat?  -Take the Fifth.
菲爾覺得我又老又胖
Seriously, Phil here thinks  I got fat with old age.
你是宰相肚裏能撐船
You're a big man with an even bigger heart.
- 看吧！  - 她說你胖
-There you go!  -She says you're chubby.
我先回旅館了，好嗎？  玩得開心
I think I'm going to go back to the hotel.  Okay? Have fun.
我喜歡這女人
I love this woman.
別讓他惹太多麻煩
Don't let him get into too much trouble.
等我們結束後  他一定會被彈劾
They'll have grounds for impeachment  when we're done with him.
趁他們關門前再拿酒來
We better get another drink  before they close up.
你來幫我拿
You're comin' with me to help carry them.
你今晚就是服務生了
You're gonna be the waiter tonight.
真懶惰
Lazy-ass cadet. Lazy-ass cadet.
幫我撐著
Hold on a second there, partner.
- 你不知道我們要來嗎？  - 完全沒想到
-You had no idea we were coming?  -Complete surprise.
- 我以為希更斯…  - 他演得很好
-I thought Higgins might've...  -No, he played it perfectly.
- 讓我以為你們不來了  - 開什麼玩笑？
-Made me think you weren't coming at all.  -Are you kidding?
我們不可能錯過的
We wouldn't have missed it for the world.
圖書館的題字  是寫法蘭還是法蘭斯？
On the library,  are they gonna put Frank or Francis?
法蘭斯
Francis.
和我國會大樓辦公室  門上的名字一樣
It's the same as the name above the door  in my office in the Capitol.
圖書館用法蘭斯比較好  法蘭像是保險桿貼紙
Francis is better for libraries.  Frank is better for bumper stickers.
我有一些
I got a few of those.
有人叫你法蘭斯嗎？
Does anybody ever actually call you Francis?
只有克萊兒
Claire does. She's the only one.
娶到她是你的福氣
She seems like a real prize.
沒錯
She is.
酒吧已經關了  但看我找到什麼
Bar was already shut down,  but look what I scored.
你好，卡羅琳
Hey, Caroline.
你想做什麼？
What do you want?
保羅在嗎？
Is Paul around?
保羅，是你請他來的嗎？
Paul, did you invite him here?
我們討論過別再讓他煩你
Did you ask him here  after we said all those times
你還請他來？
that we're not gonna let him bother you?
- 他把你害得太慘了  - 你在說什麼？
-He screwed you over one too many times.  -Who you talking about?
彼得魯索在門外
I'm talking about Peter Russo  at the front door.
是你請他來的？  還是他自己來的？
Did you ask him here,  or did he just come on his own?
他知道我們跟他撇清後…
Does he know as soon as  we're finished with him...
閉嘴
Stop.
在你跟他講清楚  叫他滾蛋前我不會閉嘴的
No, I'm not gonna stop until you  actually deal with it and get rid of him.
- 保羅，能談談嗎？  - 沒什麼好談的
-Paul, you got a minute to talk?  -There's nothing to talk about.
我想為上次  在華府見面時的事道歉
I want to apologize for when  I saw you last time in Washington,
我對你的態度
how I treated you.
就這樣？
Is that it?
我想談談造船廠的事
And I want to talk about the shipyard.
我有個計劃能彌補
I got a plan to fix it.
不要把錢都放在退休帳戶
You don't want everything going  into the Roth lRA.
一年存個五千至一萬
Five, ten grand a year,
我會幫你安排多元投資計劃
and I'll set you up with  a nice diversified package,
低風險，高收益
Iow risk, high yield.
我和克萊兒已經有計劃了
I think Claire and I have things  pretty well under control.
如果我能讓資深議員  投資我的基金
If I brought a senior U.S. Congressman  into the fund,
我在公司的地位就不一樣了
that would really up my stock  in the company.
你們在後面聊什麼？
What're you all gabbing about back there?
在聊舊圖書館
We were talkin' about the old library.
舊館會怎麼處理？
Yeah, what's happening to it?
- 拆掉嗎？  - 不知道
-They gonna tear it down?  -I don't know.
可以改造成學生中心
They could gut it,  they could turn it into a student center.
我們應該溜進去
Hey, we should sneak in there.
就像以前一樣
Like we used to.
- 好  - 我加入
-Do it.  -I'm game.
有何不可？
What the hell, why not?
可以了
There you go, that's it.
這裏是圖書館！
It's a library!
工業會大約有  三百萬元的緊急預備金
The Association had about $3 million  saved up in reserve for emergencies.
但分給一萬兩千人後  就剩沒多少了
But you split that up  between 12,000 members, it's nothing.
只夠兩周的買菜錢
Couple weeks' groceries.
我在計劃一個提案
There's a bill I'm working on.
會有大量聯邦補助
Major federal funds going towards
建設公園、綠色商業用地  重整廢棄地區
public parks, green commercial spaces,  cleaning up waste sites.
會有建地工作  公園管理，零售業…
That's construction jobs,  park management, retail...
有多少機會？
How many?
- 五千  - 一半都不到…
-Five thousand jobs.  -That's not even half...
- 只是開始  - 多快？
-It's a start.  -How soon?
- 一到兩年…  - 兩年？
-A year, maybe two...  -Two fucking years?
這期間我們要怎麼辦？
What're we supposed to do until then?
明天有個社區會議…
Listen, there's a community  meeting tomorrow...
- 我有聽說  - 我會解釋所有細節
-I heard.  -I'm gonna go over everything in detail.
- 你會去嗎？  - 沒打算
-You gonna be there?  -I wasn't planning on it.
我希望你能去
I'd like you to be there.
- 大家都很尊敬你  - 你要我替你擔保？
-Everybody respects you.  -You want me to vouch for you?
聽著，我告訴一件事  只有少數人知道
Listen, I'm gonna tell you something  that only a handful of people know.
我要競選州長
I'm running for governor.
不久就會宣佈
I announce soon.
但我要先得到工業會的支持
But I need the Association behind me  before I do that.
我知道造船廠的事  我讓你失望
Now I know I let you down with the shipyard,
但如果我贏得州長選舉  就可以導正所有事
but if I win the governor's race  I can get everything back on track.
你來我家要我原諒你
You show up on my doorstep  asking for my forgiveness,
還要我當哈巴狗？
and now you want me to be your lapdog?
在我失業之後？
After I lost my fucking job?
分水嶺提案只是開始
Okay, this Watershed Bill  is just the beginning.
我當上州長，就能做更多
If I'm governor, there's so much I can do.
放屁，你只想利用我
Yeah, it's bullshit. You just want to use me.
- 不是這樣  - 就是這樣
-It's not like that.  -Yeah, it's exactly like that.
天啊，你這個政客
Jesus Christ. You fucking politicians.
保羅…
Paul...
克萊兒
Claire.
沒想到你和法蘭住在這裏
I didn't realize you and Frank  were staying here.
我們每次來查爾斯頓  都住這裏
We always stay here  when we're in Charleston.
你知道的，瑞米  2008年的選舉…
You know that, Remy. The '08 campaign...
我發誓這只是巧合  是我助理訂的
I promise it was a coincidence.  My assistant booked it.
法蘭在嗎？
Is Frank around?
不在，他和老同學出去玩了
He's not. He's off cavorting  with his old classmates.
要坐下喝一杯嗎？
You want to sit down and have a drink?
他們幫我訂了新娘套房  還有冰香檳…
They booked me the bridal suite.  There's champagne on ice...
天啊，你比替法蘭斯工作時  有自信多了
My, my, you've grown very confident  since you worked for Francis.
我一直都很有自信，克萊兒
I've always been confident, Claire.
- 你以前絕不敢邀我上樓  - 我沒住過新娘套房
-You never would've invited me upstairs.  -Never had the bridal suite.
隨扈只能住  在四條街外的平價旅館
The staff always stayed  in the Best Western four blocks away.
好好享受你的香檳吧
Enjoy your champagne.
我只想邀你喝一杯  沒別的意思
I wasn't suggesting anything more  than a drink.
真的嗎？
Weren't you?
只是出於禮貌
Purely being polite.
晚安，瑞米
Good night, Remy.
如果你改變主意  新娘套房就在頂樓
The bridal suite's on the top floor,  at the end of the hallway,
走廊的盡頭
ifyou change your mind.
晚安，克萊兒
Good night, Claire.
肯尼，你現在太大只了
Hey, Kenny, I think you got  a little too big for this.
我覺得洞變小了
I think the hole got a lot smaller.
別讓你的肚子阻止你
Don't let a little girth stop you.
你們看
Look, look, look.
- 你找到了  - 看，還在
-You found it.  -Yeah, look, it's still there.
你們看
Wow, look at that.
步槍兵1981
菲爾藍登- 法蘭安德沃  提姆考伯- 肯卡斯威
你好
Hey.
很好，你呢？
Good, and you?
我在查爾斯頓
I'm in Charleston, actually.
你在這裏做什麼？
What are you doing here?
想給你驚喜
I thought I'd surprise you.
驚喜
Surprise.
來吧，讓你看看  我度過青春期的地方
Come on, let me show you  where I went through puberty.
我完全能想像  你16歲住在這裏的樣子
I can totally see you here at 16.
在這床上惹過不少麻煩吧？
Got in some trouble on this bed, huh?
把整條街都吵醒了
Woke up the whole block.
保羅的事如何？
Hey, how'd it go with Paul?
他叫我滾
He told me to fuck off.
我媽也用她獨特的方式  對我這樣說
Which is what my mother told me,  in her own special way.
- 我會見到她嗎？  - 你不會想見她的
-Am I gonna meet her?  -You don't want to meet her.
我只想過去問候她，看看她
I just want to stop by, say hey, see her face.
克裏絲汀娜  你來找我真的很貼心
Christina, it was really sweet  of you to come up here.
說真的
Seriously.
我深信  你是我交往過最棒的女人
I'm officially convinced that you're  the most amazing woman I've ever been with.
但我說我要獨自來這裏時  也是認真的
But I meant it when I said  I wanted to take this trip alone.
明天會是場硬仗
This thing tomorrow isn't gonna be pleasant.
所以我才來，給你精神支持
Which is why I came.  To be here for you. Moral support.
我瞭解這些人  他們一定會狠狠教訓我
I know these people,  they're going to lay into me big time.
明天對競選很重要
Tomorrow's an important day  for the campaign.
別跟我爭
Don't fight me on this.
好吧
Okay.
我是去住旅館呢？
So do I get a hotel?
還是留在這裏？
Do I stay here?
別這樣
Come on, don't be like that.
旅館舒服多了
A hotel would be more comfortable.
別浪費寶貴的競選資金
But it would be a waste  of valuable campaign funds.
競選資金
Oh, campaign funds.
有看到天花板上的裂痕嗎？
You see that crack up in the ceiling?
我以前每晚都盯著它入睡
I used to fall asleep staring at it every night.
對它瞭若指掌
I know every inch and curve.
這裏好暗，我怕黑！
It's dark in here. I'm scared of the dark!
走開！
Get out of the way!
- 小心！  - 賭注很大
-Hey, hey!  -Big fucking gamble, my man.
光來了！
Let there be light!
你在想什麼？
What are you thinking about?
你和法蘭怎麼沒有小孩？
How come you and Frank  have never had kids?
- 你也沒有小孩  - 但我沒結婚
-You've never had kids.  -Yeah, but I'm not married.
回答問題
Answer the question.
是我們決定的
We just decided not to.
沒有討論很久
There wasn't some big conversation.
我覺得你在說謊
I think you're lying.
隨你怎麼想
Think whatever you want.
你真的沒想過嗎？
You honestly never thought about it?
有過一兩次吧
I mean, yeah, maybe once or twice.
我不覺得遺憾
I mean, I don't feel there's some void.
沒有小孩我也很幸福
I'm perfectly happy without.
你呢？
What about you?
你能想像我  幫小孩擦屁股、換尿布嗎？
Can you imagine me wiping a baby's ass  and changing nappies?
不能
No, I can't.
其實我剛想像了一下  我得掛電話了
Actually, yes, I just did,  I'm going to have to get off the phone.
那畫面太糟了
You've ruined everything.
真的該掛了  已經講一個多小時了
We really should get off.  It's been over an hour I think.
好
Okay.
掛吧
Go on then.
- 我現在就掛  - 我先掛
-I'm hanging up right now.  -No, I am.
- 衝啊，肯  - 衝啊
-Yeah! Let's go, Ken, let's go.  -Go, go, go.
加油，別放棄
Yeah, come on. Giddy up, come on.  Don't quit on me.
- 不知道數幾下了  - 加油，別放棄
-I lost count.  -Come on, don't quit on me. Don't quit.
天啊
No. Oh, God.
你贏了
You win.
但這不公平
But it's not a fair fight.
你開泛舟公司  我整天坐在辦公桌前
You run a rafting company.  I sit behind a desk all day.
很想看你拿著槳  劃過四級激流的樣子
I'd love to see your ass with a paddle  bouncing through a class-four rapid.
如果我能讓國會屈服  一點小激流算不上什麼
If I can whip Congress into submission,  I'm not afraid of a little white water.
你無法馴服激流的，法蘭
You can't tame a rapid, Frank.
我心跳得好快  我如果心臟病發是你害的
My heart is beating so fast.  If I have a heart attack it's your fault.
我的也是
Mine too.
摸摸看
Here.
我需要再喝一杯
I need another drink.
我也是
I think I'll have another, too.
別喝光了
Don't bogart that.
這個地方造就我們嗎？
Do you think this place made us?
什麼意思？
How do you mean?
我今天走過校園時在想  這裏有意義嗎？
When I walked on campus today I wondered,  did it mean anything?
這只是我們生活四年的地方  還有更深的意義嗎？
If it's just a place we spent four years  of our lives or was there more?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我知道
I do know you were always the guy
會有建築物以你命名
who was going to get  a building named after him.
當我看到你罵那個訓練中士  就知道了
I knew that the moment I saw you  cuss out the drill sergeant
我們當時還是小毛頭
when we were knobs.
圖書館是個騙局
The library is a sham.
希更斯找我幫忙  我找別人幫忙
Higgins asked me a favor,  I asked someone else a favor,
他們就把我的名字放上去了
they slapped my name on it.
政治跟其他事情都一樣
Politics. Like everything else.
不是每個人都能幫這種忙
Not everybody gets asked those favors.
或是知道怎麼達成
Or knows how to deliver on them.
50年後，他們就會換掉匾額
In 50 years, they'll just replace it  with something else,
就像他們把我換掉一樣
just like they're doing with this for mine.
你還是有建樹，不管維持多久
You still built something.  However long it lasts.
圖書館不重要
The library doesn't matter.
但我希望這個地方有意義
But I want to think that this place did.
對當年的我們意義深遠
I think it meant a lot to us, then.
那我們呢？
And what about us?
老實說，我沒想那麼多
Honestly, I haven't really  thought about it that much.
都是陳年往事了
It's a long time ago.
我們之前那麼親密
We were so close.
像兄弟一樣
Like brothers.
比兄弟更親
More than brothers.
我們只是孩子，法蘭
We were kids, Frank.
胡搞了幾次
We messed around a couple of times.
我深深被你吸引…
I was so drawn to you...
我總是能逗你笑
I could always make you laugh.
我們怎麼會失去連絡？
How did we lose touch?
你進了法學院，我去從軍
You went to law school. I joined the army.
你去競選議員  我搬去科羅拉多州
You ran for Congress. I moved to Colorado.
30年過去了
Thirty years goes by.
我的孩子都比我們當年大了
I got children older than we were back then.
法蘭，你有對象嗎？
Do you have anyone, Frank?
我有克萊兒
I have Claire.
除了她之外
Besides Claire.
有時候有
I have, from time to time.
如果我要誰，就會得到
If I want someone, I want them.
這是吸引力
It's attraction.
你能快樂我就快樂，法蘭
It made me happy to make you happy, Frank.
沒什麼不好的
Didn't see any harm in it.
知道我為何喜歡泛舟？
You know why I love rafting?
在水上的時候
When you're on the water,
你只會想著眼前的一切
all you're thinking about  is what's right in front of you.
一切都在當下
Everything is in the moment.
我沒時間去想過去
I don't really have time  to think about the past.
你對我意義重大
You meant something to me.
我相信
I believe that.
喝完了
All gone.
- 我不太舒服…  - 你要吐嗎？
-I don't feel so well...  -You gonna be sick?
不，我只是…
No. No, I just...
休息一下
Take a break.
我們可以休息一下嗎？  等我舒服一點
Can we just stay here for a little bit?  Until I feel better.
慢慢休息吧
Take as long as you like.
我也沒地方去
I got nowhere to go.
- 再過幾周就解脫了  - 再過幾周就解脫了
-A few more weeks and we'll be through.  -A few more weeks and we'll be through.
- 我就不必再看到你  - 我就不必再看到你
-And I won't have to look at you.  -And I won't have to look at you.
- 你長得真醜  - 你長得真醜
-Ugly, ugly, ugly you.  -Ugly, ugly, ugly you.
克萊兒
快7點了
It's almost 7:00.
我根本不記得自己有睡著…
I don't even remember going to sleep...
走吧
Come on.
- 1100英畝的開發案  - 對
-1,100 acres of development.  -Yes.
- 30%是公園  - 對
-30% public parks.  -Yep.
- 45%是購物辦公空間  - 對
-45% shopping and office space.  -Yes.
25%是中產階級住宅
25% middle-income housing.
你要去嗎？
You going?
- 一定要嗎？  - 應該不是
-ls it required?  -I don't think so.
他們用來命名圖書館的  那個人是誰？
Who is he that they're  naming the place after?
以前在這裏讀書的校友  我猜已經死了
Some guy who went here. I think he's dead.
我們昨天得去排椅子  熱得要死
We had to set up the chairs yesterday.  It was hot as shit.
真慘
That sucks.
儀式前我要瞇一下
I'm gonna try to get some shut-eye  before the ceremony.
等會見？
I'll see you all later?
- 等會見  - 法蘭，趁我還記得
-Later it is.  -Hey, Frank, before I forget,
這是我的名片  請你的理財經理打給我
here's my card,  so your money manager can call me.
休息一下
Get some rest.
克萊兒
Claire.
你看起來好痛苦
You look like you're hurting.
玩了整晚
It was an all-nighter.
- 至少很開心吧？  - 很開心，我得去休息一下
-Was it fun at least?  -lt was fun. I need to get some shut-eye.
瑞米住在這裏
Remy's staying here.
他又拿募款的事騷擾你了？
He harassing you about the donation?
沒有我不能應付的事  去休息一下吧
Oh, nothing I can't handle. Go get some rest.
- 你厲害嗎？  - 還不錯
-Were you good?  -Not bad.
我不是先發球員  但還是有常上場
I wasn't a starter,  but I got my time on the court.
你長大後比較性感
I think you look sexier now, all grown up.
議員？
Congressman?
我們準備好了
We're ready for you.
你說兩年
You said two years.
我相信兩年是合理的評估
Yeah, I think two years is a realistic estimate.
- 如果有通過的話  - 我相信會的
-If it passes at all.  -Which I think it will.
相信還是知道？
You think or you know?
我不敢說百分之百  但我有信心
I can't predict 100%, but I'm confident it will.
你相信，你有信心  你不敢說百分之百
You think, you're confident,  you can't predict 100%,
對我們有幫助嗎？
how does any of that help us?
我告訴你
I'll tell you something,
我百分之百付不出房貸
I'm 100% unable  to pay my mortgage right now.
我百分之百沒辦法  幫我孩子買文具
I'm 100% unable to buy  my kids school supplies.
我們該靠先生的殘障津貼  過日子嗎？
We supposed to live off  my husband's disability?
會有支薪的訓練課程
There'll be paid training programs available.
薪水多少？
How much will they pay?
比你們在造船廠的工資少
Granted, it's less than you made  at the shipyard.
- 多少？  - 一小時六塊錢
-So how much?  -It's about $6 an hour.
還不到最低工資
That's not even minimum wage.
- 放屁，魯索！  - 你們要把這當成投資
-Horseshit, Russo!  -You have to see it as an investment.
訓練課程也是珍貴資源…
The training programs  are a valuable resource...
你沒聽懂
You're not getting it.
我沒辦法投資
I can't afford to make investments.
一小時六塊錢  等於叫我全家流落街頭
$6 an hour puts my family on the street.
你要我打五份工嗎？
What, do you want me to work five jobs?
如果你們有一份兼職  加上訓練課程…
If you get a part-time job,  that and the training program...
想知道我的想法嗎？
You want to know what I think?
你坐在華府  想出一堆漂亮數字的提案
I think you sit around in Washington  coming up with all sorts of fancy numbers
都是紙上談兵  但對我們都沒有幫助
and solutions that look good on paper,  but that doesn't cut it for the rest of us.
你說過支持我們，說謊！
You said you had our backs,  you lying piece of shit!
紙不能吃，也不能遮風避雨
We don't eat paper for dinner.  You can't put a paper roof over your head.
我們投票給你的時候
When we all voted for you,
沒想到這些選票  都是我們自己棺材上的釘子
I didn't think that every one of those votes  was another nail in our own coffins.
拜託大家坐下，十分鐘就好
Please, everybody,  just sit down for 10 minutes,
我們能逐項討論這個提案
we can go over this proposal point-by-point.
這樣你們就會  有足夠的資訊和資源…
And you can get the information you need  to get the resources that you want...
- 他們好像不想解決  - 他們是害怕
-It's like they don't want to find a solution.  -They're scared.
我知道他們害怕  但不表示不能聽你說…
I understand that they're scared,  but that doesn't mean they can't listen...
你不瞭解他們，克裏絲汀娜
You don't know these people, Christina.
我替你工作三年了
I worked in your office for three years.
我跟他們講話，接他們的電話  回他們的郵件…
I spoke to them, I took their calls,  I replied to their emails...
你沒有和他們一起長大
You didn't grow up with them.
我不需要和他們一起長大  才能同情他們的處境…
I don't need to grow up hand-to-mouth  to empathize with the fact that...
他們不需要同情
They're not interested in empathy.
房間鑰匙在我外套裏
The house keys are in my jacket.
我再打給你
I'll call you.
- 彼得  - 我說我會再打給你
-Peter.  -I said I'll call you.
寫功課之類的…
Do your homework or Sister Mary Joseph...
你根本沒做…別騙我  我以前用一樣的藉口騙我父母
You didn't do it... Don't lie to me.  I used to use the same ploy with my parents.
胡扯
Baloney.
寫完功課再吃飯
We do the homework,  and then we eat.
誰餓了？
Who's hungry?
- 你們想吃什麼？  - 漢堡
-What do you guys want?  -Hamburger.
- 披薩  - 不行
-Pizza.  -No.
不吃披薩，你們每天都…
No pizza, you guys can eat that every...
親愛的，帶孩子們上樓
Sweetheart, take the kids upstairs.
你怎麼進來的？
How'd you get in here?
你還是把鑰匙  放在門廊的鬆動磚頭後面
You still keep the spare key behind  the loose brick on the porch.
你闖進我家？  那樣嚇壞我的孩子？
You break into my house?  You scare my kids like that?
- 我們得談談，保羅  - 昨晚談過了
-We gotta talk, Paul.  -We talked last night.
馬上滾
Now get out.
我可以說服他們  但我需要你的幫忙
I can convince these people,  but I need your help.
- 離開我家  - 坐下
-Leave my house.  -Sit down.
我孩子在樓上  我不想打你，彼得
I don't want to have to hurt you  with my children upstairs, Petey.
那就幫我
Then help me.
最後一次機會
This is your last chance.
我不走
I'm not going anywhere.
回樓上！
Get back upstairs!
我們在做什麼？
What are we doing?
我不想跟你打架，彼得
I don't want to fight you, Petey.
我也不想
I don't want to fight you either.
我可以，但我們不需要這樣
I will, but we don't have to.
你要我做什麼？
What do you want me to do?
你們選我來代表你們  但我無法阻止不可避免的事
You elected me to represent you.  But I couldn't forestall the inevitable.
造船廠關閉了
The shipyard was closing.
就算今年不關，明後年也會關  我們心知肚明
If not this year, then next, or the year after.  We all know that.
我可以騙你們  我可以假裝多做一些事
I could have lied to you.  I could have pretended to do more.
但我不想活在過去
But I don't believe in living in the past.
我只關心未來
I only care about the future.
接下來的事實可能不好聽…
Here's another truth  that's gonna be hard to swallow...
你們只能靠我了
I'm all you've got.
華府沒人管你們的死活
Nobody in Washington gives  a fuck about you. No one.
他說得對
He's right.
不管你們對彼得有何想法  我們不跟著他，就一無所有
Whatever you think of Petey,  we either go with him or we got nothing.
我的提議符合  你們的需要或標準嗎？
Now does what I'm offering you come  anywhere near what you want or deserve?
沒有
No.
但你們得睜大雙眼  把握眼前的東西
But you gotta open your eyes  and take what's in front of you.
我們能慢慢發展
We can build on that.
五千份工作變成一萬  然後變成一萬五千
5,000 jobs becomes 10, then 15.
這不會一夕成真  但總比什麼都不做來得好
Not in the snap of a finger,  but faster than doing nothing will.
我可以指望你們嗎？
Can I count on all ofyou?
我就當你們答應了
All right, I'll take that as a yes.
我們要你們的連絡方式
We'll need your contact information,
才能把資料傳給你們  分享給朋友
so we can send you materials  to share with your friends.
現在討論資金要怎麼引入
Now, let's talk about the way  the money's gonna get phased in.
總共有六階段，第一階段…
It's gonna happen in six stages. Stage one...
左轉，齊步走
Left face, forward march.
法蘭斯安德沃的職業生涯  哈佛法學院
Francis Underwood's career,  Harvard Law degree,
南卡羅來納州史上  最年輕的州議員之一
one of the youngest state legislators  in the history of South Carolina,
美國國會22年的資深議員
a 22-year veteran of the U.S. Congress,
眾議院多數黨黨鞭
House Majority Whip,
充分證明年輕人  在山特諾學到的價值觀
speaks volumes about the values  young people learn here at the Sentinel,
像是榮譽、責任、紀律
values like honor, duty, discipline,
犧牲、服務和尊敬
Iike sacrifice, service and respect.
女士先生們  法蘭斯安德沃圖書館
Ladies and Gentlemen,  the Francis J. Underwood library.
議員？
Congressman?
謝謝
Thank you.
我寫了一段演講稿
I wrote a speech.
但我不打算念
But I'm not gonna read it.
沒有什麼是永恆的  這棟建築物也一樣
Nothing is permanent.  Not even this building.
我無意顯得忘恩負義
I don't mean to sound ungrateful.
我很感恩，也非常榮幸
I am very grateful, I'm deeply honored,
非常感動
and I am very moved.
我這週末有幸  能和一群朋友一起度過
I had the good fortune of spending most  of this weekend with a group of friends.
一群好久不見的老友
Friends I haven't seen in a very long time.
一群我在這裏交的朋友
Friends I made here.
大部分的年輕學生  可能不知道我是誰
Most of you young cadets  probably don't know who I am.
只是政客  一個有少數成就的名字
Politician. A name. A few accomplishments.
但我不怪你們
But I don't blame you.
我和你們一樣大的時候
When I was your age, why,
我也不太在乎  那些老頭子做過什麼
I didn't care much for what  men in gray hair did
或是要說什麼
or what they had to say.
我希望我能形容…
I wish I could describe...
和諧  這個詞在我腦中揮之不去
Harmony.  That's the word that's stuck in my mind.
和諧
Harmony.
這和永恆的事物無關
It's not about what's lasting or permanent.
而是個人的聲音
It is about individual voices
在一瞬間集結在一起
coming together for a moment,
那一瞬間
and that moment lasts
只有一口氣那麼長
the length of a breath.
這就是我對這個地方的感覺
That's what I think about my time here.
請原諒我  我昨晚多喝了幾杯威士忌
You'll have to forgive me.  I had more than a few whiskeys last night.
當我還是學生  我們可以喝整晚的酒
You know, when I was a cadet,  we could drink all night,
然後早上起來行軍30公里
then get up in the morning  and march 20 miles,
現在能走上這三階樓梯  就不錯了
but these days I'm lucky  I got up these three steps.
非常感謝你們
I want to thank you very much.
這是至高的榮耀
This is a great honor.
感謝希更斯校長
I want to thank President Higgins,
當然還有我此生的摯愛  克萊兒
and of course, the love of my life, Claire.
謝謝各位
Thank you all very much.
- 你還好吧？  - 還好
-Are you okay?  -Yes.
媽
Hey, Ma.
這是克裏絲汀娜  我昨天跟你提過她
This is Christina.  I told you about her yesterday.
- 你好，魯索太太  - 你好
-Hi, Mrs. Russo.  -Hey.
我們只是來跟你說再見  火車一小時後就要開了
We just came by to say goodbye.  We have to catch a train in about an hour.
好
Okay.
他們還是沒來修燈嗎？
They still haven't fixed that light?
今天蠻順利的
Things went well today.
我覺得造船廠的人會支持我
I think the folks in the yard  are going to get behind me.
彼得做得很棒
Peter did a great job.
把毯子拿給我
Hand me that blanket.
這裏的冷氣瘋了
AC in here is nuts.
你的手怎麼了？
What happened to your hand?
- 跟人打架  - 贏了嗎？
-I got in a fight.  -Did you win?
算是吧
Yeah. I guess I did.
這才是我的彼得
That's my Peter.
你跟我兒子上床了嗎？
So you're fucking my son?
笑一個，我在鬧你而已
Lighten up. I'm just messing with ya.
- 不好意思  - 等一下
-Excuse me?  -Hold on a second.
- 什麼事？  - 我媽媽在409號病房
-Yeah?  -Yeah, my mother's in room 409.
她有個燈管需要換
She has a light out that needs to be replaced.
- 我會去換  - 謝謝
-All right. I'll take care of it.  -Okay, thanks.
寶貝，如果你穿粉紅色  我告訴你…
Look, baby, you put that pink thing on,  I'm telling you. It's just...
你要我穿什麼？  你要我穿那件小…
What you want me to wear?  You want me to wear that little...
等一下，怎麼了？
Hold on. What is it?
我媽媽病房裏的燈
The light in my mother's room.
我說了等等就去換
Right. I told you I'll take care of it later.
現在就去
No. You'll take care of it now.
我得掛了
I gotta go.
順便把冷氣溫度調高一點
And turn the AC down  while you're in there, too.
好
Yes, sir.
謝謝
Thank you very much.
- 不客氣  - 保重
-You're very welcome, sir.  -Take care of yourselves.
我們真為你驕傲，法蘭
Real proud of you, Frank.
雖然不想承認  但我也這麼認為
I hate to admit it, but I feel the same.
你們來參加  才會讓一切這麼特別
Well, having all you here  is what made it special.
- 保持連絡  - 一定
-Now, you stay in touch.  -Will do.
再見
See you, buddy.
很美的儀式，法蘭
Beautiful ceremony, Frank.
他們辦得不錯
Yeah, they did a good job.
你的演講
Your speech.
很高興我能在現場聽到
I'm glad I was here for that.
我也是
Me too.
你應該找時間來薩利達  我帶你去阿肯色河
You should come out to Salida sometime.  I'll take you out on the Arkansas River.
是應該這麼做
I should do that.
隨時歡迎
Anytime you want.
好
Yep.
All right.
法蘭斯…
Francis...
愛德華把車準備好了
Edward has the car ready.
我馬上來
I'll be right there.
慢慢來
Take your time.
- 有彼得的消息嗎？  - 已經拉攏造船廠的人了
-You hear from Peter?  -Looks like the shipbuilders are on board.
明早開始寫  他宣佈參選的演講稿
Tomorrow morning we start working  on his draft for his announcement speech.
好
Got it.
我要分水嶺提案的審議簡報…
And I want the brief on the mark-up  for the Watershed Bill...
我準備好了
I got that with me.
跟我一起去機場  我們在車裏討論
Ride with me to the airport,  we can go through it in the car.